Your Majesty, it's my great honor
承蒙城主不棄
that I could become your sworn sister.
與屬下義結金蘭
During the battle with Xuanhu,
屬下與玄虎一役
I was severely injured and I'll die soon.
身負重傷 命不久矣
Since I'll no longer be able to take care of my baby daughter Chuchu,
膝下 有幼女楚楚無人照看
I hope I can entrust her to you,
我欲將其託付於城主
in the hope of that she can grow up to be useful and be my successor
盼她成材 繼我衣缽
(In memorial of late Minister Pei Wujiang) to devote herself to Huayuan City!
報效花垣
Hope I can be useful
盼我成材
and be her successor
繼承衣缽
to devote myself to Huayuan!
報效花垣
Turns out I can never
原來我生來
be the City Owner!
就無法做城主
Then why did you
那為何
give me the hope?
又要給我希望
Chuchu.
楚楚
You know already?
你 都知道了
You've known it all along, haven't you?
你也早知道了吧
So has Chen Qianqian, right?
陳芊芊也知道吧
You all knew it,
你們都知道
but no one told me.
卻偏偏不告訴我
Turns out
讓我白白
I've been daydreaming!
做了一場大夢
Mother, you asked me to be here today...
母親 你今日叫我來
I know you came to Xuanhu in a hurry
我知道你這次來得匆忙
and didn't pack a lot of stuff,
什麼都沒帶
so I prepared some cloth
特意讓他們給你準備了些布料
and jewelry for you.
還有些首飾
Take a look! Do you like it?
你看 喜歡嗎
I do!
喜歡
If you do,
你要是喜歡
it's all yours.
這些都是你的
This is...
這
Put... Put this back.
先 先放回去
Mother, you can hold it with one hand?
單手啊 母親
You are so strong!
力氣挺大
If I wear the armor
我 現在這身行頭
instead of this dress,
跟上陣的鎧甲相比
I'll be stronger!
還差太遠了
Mother,
母親
Han Shuo told me
我聽韓爍說
that your father used to be the Minister of Defense of Xuanhu.
您父親生前也是玄虎城的司軍
I guess you became his successor later.
看來你是繼承了老司軍的衣缽
So, were you also a Minister before you got married?
那你 出嫁前也是司軍嗎
I was still young back then.
那時候還年幼無知
My father was badly ill,
當年 正值我父親病重
and we were about to lose the war,
又戰事告急
so I disguised myself as a man to fight on the battlefield
我只好女扮男裝 混進軍隊
on my father's behalf.
替父出征
May I ask your last name?
敢問母親姓氏
My last name is Hua.
我姓花
Hua?
花
It's more and more like the story I'm familiar with.
更像我熟知的那個故事了
I met your father
就是那次出征
during that battle.
我結識了你的父親
He was an Army Supervisor at that time.
那時候他還是監軍少君
I fought him one-on-one
我與他切磋時
for a whole hour
把他單挑下馬
and made him fall off the horse in the end.
我打了他足足半個時辰
Then why don't you wanna be the Minister of Defense now?
那母親為何現在不去當司軍了
I'm the City Owner's wife.
我畢竟是城主夫人
I need to keep my decent and elegant posture in front of people.
人前要做你父親舉止得體的妻子
With time goes by,
這時間一長啊
I've got used to this domestic life.
假的也變成真的了
Don't you feel regret?
那你不後悔嗎
I'm interested in the art of war
我喜歡兵法
and I like leading the army.
喜歡帶兵打仗
But I love your father more!
但是我更愛你的父親
Plus, I gave birth to Han Shuo;
我還生育了韓爍
I taught him all the knowledge and martial art skills
我把我的學識 見聞 武藝
I've mastered.
都教給他
For them,
為了他們
I never regret for what I gave up.
我放棄這些 沒有後悔
But Han Shuo has
可是現在韓爍已經長大了
grown up.
成人了
You never thought about returning to the battlefield again?
你就沒有想過再次帶兵嗎
It never crossed my mind.
以前不敢想
After all,
畢竟
it's very difficult for a woman
女人想要家庭的同時
to take care of family and career at the same time.
還想要事業是很難的一件事情
I'm not good at
這兩者如何兼顧
balancing these two.
我不擅長
Not necessarily.
不會呀
In Huayuan City,
在花垣城
women are in charge of earning bread
女人賺錢養家 當家做主
and men are responsible for housework.
男人操持家務
It actually works pretty well.
這也是很和諧的
Why does it work in Huayuan,
為什麼花垣城可以
but not in Xuanhu?
玄虎城就不行
But the men of Huayuan
可花垣男子
also cannot do whatever they want
與我玄虎女子一般
just like the women of Xuanhu.
也不能隨心做自己想做的事
I created Huayuan and made women superior to men
我創造花垣 女尊男卑
so that women could live proudly.
本想是讓女人揚眉吐氣一番
But I've never thought about men's situation.
卻從未考慮過花垣男子的境遇
It's still not fair.
這不還是一樣不公平嗎
Looks like there really are some problems with my play.
看來 我的劇本確實有些問題
Men work very hard to support the family.
男子在外養家
It's not proper to let them do housework.
不好讓他們操持家務
Then I wanna ask you, mother, what's family?
那我想問母親 何為家庭
It requires both husband and wife to make a family.
夫婦一體 乃為家
It takes two to build a family,
兩個人在一起的才是家庭
so maintaining the family
維繫家庭的
shouldn't be one's job,
不應該是其中一個人的責任
right?
對嗎
My birth mother was former Minister Pei.
我親生母親是前任裴司軍
She entrusted me to Her Majesty
她把我託付給城主
so that I could be the next Minster of Defense.
就是為了要讓我繼任司軍的
That's why I grew up learning literature and Kung Fu,
所以 我從小到大學文習武
and I was appointed as filler-in Minister
沒有經歷擢考
without even going through election.
就被點名暫代司軍一職
I was supposed
司軍之位
to be the Minster of Defense!
本來就是我的
But Mr. Pei
可現在
has become the Minister now.
司軍是裴公子
That's why
所以
I first need to take back the thing that originally belonged to me!
我要先拿回原本屬於我的東西
Why should I
我為什麼要走
follow others' arrangement?
別人給我安排好的路
Chen Qianqian is gone,
陳芊芊走了
so they want me to be the Crown Princess.
她們便想讓我當少城主
No, I will not!
我偏不
Minister Pei.
裴司軍
In half a month,
半月之後
we'll deliver another batch of black stone minerals
我們將有一批新的烏石礦
to Xuanhu City.
送往玄虎城
Given the tense relationship between the two cities,
如今兩城關係緊張
shall we send more people to deliver the minerals?
我們是否要多派些人手去護送
No need.
不必了
We are going there for business, not for a war.
我們是去做生意 不是打仗
It'll be fine sending a small troop
派一小隊人馬
to ward off bandits.
防備山賊即可
Try to avoid conflict with Xuanhu City.
儘量避免與玄虎城發生衝突
Conflict is not something you can avoid!
衝突是你想躲就能躲得過的嗎
You think we can still
你們以為與玄虎城
keep a peaceful relationship with Xuanhu as before?
還能和以前一樣和平共處嗎
Send the Second Princess back to her mansion!
送二郡主回府
I am not the Second Princess!
我不是二郡主
I am Minister Pei!
我是裴司軍
Your Highness,
二郡主
if you want to take the Minister position back,
如果您想奪回司軍之位
you'll be Minister Chen.
也應該是陳司軍
But how come you called yourself Minister Pei?
為何會是裴司軍
What if I'm the daughter of late Minister Pei?
若我是已故裴司軍的女兒呢
Your Highness, can you provide any proof?
郡主 您說這話可有證據
You must be surprised!
你沒想到吧
I don't want to be the Crown Princess anymore!
我不想做什麼少城主了
I don't want the thing that Chen Qianqian
陳芊芊不要的東西
doesn't want.
我也不要
I only want to be Minister Pei now!
我現在只想做裴司軍
Since you don't want people to know
既然哥哥不願意在人前
that I'm your younger sister,
認我這個妹妹
I'll just have to prove it myself.
那我只有自驗正身了
Minister Pei had a daughter?
裴司軍居然還有個女兒
This jade pendant
這個玉佩
did belong to late Minister Pei.
果然是已故裴司軍的東西
And the handwriting was hers, too!
這字跡也作不了假
They are all named Pei.
兩個人都姓裴
Who should we listen to?
我們到底聽誰的
Brother, that day,
當日哥哥
you took over the City Guards
是以已故裴司軍獨子的身份
in the name of late Minister Pei's only son.
收服了護城軍
But now,
那麼今日
as late Minister Pei's daughter,
我這個裴司軍的女兒
I think the Minister of Defense should be my rightful position!
是不是比一個男人更名正言順
The City Guards of Huayuan
花垣城的護城軍
have never taken orders from a man!
何時向一個男人低過頭
In order to take over the leadership,
你為了接手護城軍
you even exposed your identity?!
不惜自曝身世
Actually, you...
其實你
you didn't have to do this!
根本不必要這樣
No one would fight with you anymore!
現在已經沒人跟你爭了
Where's the flower token?
花符呢
Minster...
裴司
Mr. Pei, we're sorry!
裴公子 得罪了
From now on,
從今日起
I'll be the new Minister of Defense of Huayuan!
我就是花垣城新一任司軍
I'm the perfect fit for this position!
名正言順的裴司軍
Greetings to you, Minister Pei!
拜見裴司軍
Minster!
司軍
This is the token that commands the entire City Guards!
這可是統領護城軍的信物啊
In the future, the City Guards of Huayuan
今後 花垣城的護城軍
will follow the person instead of the token!
只認人 不認符
Whoever dares to disobey will be beheaded!
違令者 斬
-Yes!
是 是
Send him back to his mansion!
送他回府
Guards, send Mr. Pei back to his mansion!
來人 送裴公子回府
Withhold this batch of black stone minerals
半個月後的這批烏石礦
for now.
暫且扣住
But, Minister,
司軍
we've come to an agreement with Xuanhu;
這是我們早已和玄虎城談好的
they've even paid the deposit.
他們定金都已經付了
If we go back on our word,
如果我們現在反悔
it'll undermine our credibility!
豈不是自毀信譽
Xuanhu City
他玄虎城
took Huayuan's traitor princess away.
收留了我花垣城的叛城郡主
So what's the big deal if I withhold their black stone minerals?
我扣他一批礦算什麼
Traitor princess?
叛城郡主
You mean the Crown Princess is still alive?
難道是少城主 她還活著
Send my message to Xuanhu.
給玄虎城送去消息
If they want the minerals,
要礦可以
then send Chen Qianqian back first!
把陳芊芊給我送回來
Otherwise, the Han family
否則從今以後
of Xuanhu can forget
他玄虎城的韓家
about buying black stone minerals from Huayuan in the future!
休想從我手中拿走一塊烏石礦
I won't sell even for thousands of pieces of gold!
千金萬金也不賣
Minister, if Xuanhu refuses to send the Crown Princess back,
司軍 若是玄虎城不同意
the black stone minerals we dug out will lie idle
我們挖出來這些礦就這麼放著
since they are useless to us.
咱們花垣城也用不上啊
I've had a plan.
我自有安排
In addition,
另外
I don't trust the guards in the City Owner's Mansion.
城主府的護衛我信不過
Replace them with our own people.
去換我們的人
-Yes!
是 是
I heard
聽說
that you seized the Minister position back from Pei Heng.
你從裴恆手中奪回了司軍之位
I just recaptured something that belonged to me.
我只是拿回原本屬於我的東西
How can that be called seizure?
怎麼能叫作奪呢
I also heard
我又聽說
that you surrounded this mansion with lots of guards.
你將城主府保護了起來
Mother, you are tired. You need some rest.
母親 您累了 該好好歇息
I want you
女兒想讓您
to take good care of your health!
好好調養身子
But the entire Huayuan
可整個花垣城
knows that you aren't my daughter.
都知道你不是我的女兒
How will you become the City Owner now?
你還怎麼繼任城主之位
Don't worry, mother.
母親放心
I'm fine with being a Minister.
我只做司軍就好
I've thought it through.
女兒已經想通了
As long as I have the military power,
只要權力捏在手裡
it doesn't matter if I'm the City Owner.
做不做城主 又有何區別
I have the City Guards my birth mother left me.
我有我親生母親留下的護城軍
Why would I fight
我為何要與別人
for the title of City Owner?
搶一個城主的名頭
You see,
您看
I'm the commander of the army;
我現在坐鎮軍中
and the black stone mine in Huayuan
花垣城的烏石礦
is at my disposal.
我想怎麼用 就怎麼用
There's nothing you can do about it.
您不也拿我沒辦法嗎
I was afraid that you'd become like this.
我就是怕你變成今天這個樣子
That's why I didn't tell you who you really are.
所以 才不想把你的身世告訴你
You should have told me earlier.
您還不如早些告訴我真相
That would make me feel better.
我心裡還能好受一些
Looks like I was wrong.
看來 是我錯了
Back then,
當年
I just wanted you to be happy.
我只是想讓你過得開心一點
Growing up, I've always lost to Chen Qianqian
從小到大 在您面前
in front of you.
我一直都輸給陳芊芊
This time,
這次
I will prove to you
我一定要向您證明
that I'm better than her!
我比她強
Are you really
你一定
determined to kill my youngest daughter?
要我白髮人送黑髮人嗎
No worry!
您放心
I won't kill her.
我不會再殺她
But neither will I let her hide
但她也別想躲起來
and spend the rest of her life with Han Shuo!
和韓爍長相廝守
I will find her back!
我要讓她回來
I'll let her see herself
讓她看看
how she's lost to me!
她是怎麼輸給我的
So in your heart,
在你看來
you really
我在你眼裡
don't see me as your mother anymore?
就沒有半分母女情誼了嗎
Young Master, Huayuan sent a message,
少君 花垣城那面傳來消息
saying that if we don't send their Crown Princess back,
說如果不把少城主送回去
they will stop selling us the black stone minerals.
她們就不把礦賣給我們
It doesn't sound like my mother's order.
聽起來 不像是母親下達的命令
Maybe someone faked the order again!
是不是又有人越俎代庖了
I should go back and check.
要不 我回去看看吧
Obviously it's a trap Chen Chuchu set
這一看就是陳楚楚為了騙你回去
to lure you back.
設下的陷阱
They must have
花垣城那邊
fully prepared to ambush you if you go back.
現在應該是天羅地網等著你了
Let's go discuss it with my father.
我們去找父親商議
He's righteous and considerate;
他深明大義
he won't send you back
就算是為了我
for my sake.
也不會把你送回去的
Let's go!
走
Father,
父親
I've summoned a few generals of our City Guards.
我已經召集了護城軍的幾位叔伯
So,
不知您
what do you think?
意下如何
Qianqian,
芊芊啊
how have you
最近在玄虎城
been doing in Xuanhu City?
住得還習慣嗎
Very well!
習慣 習慣
Mother and you treat me like your own daughter!
父親母親待我像親女兒一樣
That's good! Very good!
那就好 那就好
That makes me feel relieved!
那我就放心了
So you will let her stay?
您是打算讓她留下
I'm glad to know that you enjoyed yourself.
玩得差不多了
And now it's time for you to go back!
也該回你們花垣城了
You'll send her to die?
您是要讓她去送死嗎
This conflict happened because of her.
此事本就因她而起
But you'd rather make our City Guards suffer
你們不僅不願意讓她承擔責任
than let her take responsibilities.
反倒犧牲我們玄虎護城軍的兄弟
What if it's a trap?
此事萬一有詐呢
Huayuan is indeed good
這花垣美人計
at using honey-trap!
當真好用啊
One after another!
一環扣一環
Haven't you learned your lesson yet?
你們怎麼吃起虧來沒完
Your Majesty, if you don't find
城主如果不從根本上
a permanent solution to the conflict,
去解決與花垣城的紛爭
Chuchu will sooner or later
楚楚繼任城主
stop trading black stone minerals with Xuanhu
早晚都會切斷
after she becomes the City Owner.
與玄虎城的烏石礦交易
By that time,
到那個時候
men in Xuanhu can only
玄虎城的男人就只能
farm for a living,
去種地了
or develop cloth business
或者像花垣城一樣
like Huayuan City
發展布料產業
and let women be the bread-earners.
女人養家餬口
Let women go to work?
女人賺錢
Then who'll be heads of household?
那誰來當家呀
Women, of course!
自然是女人啊
No way!
怎麼可能
Then Xuanhu will become another Huayuan!
那不跟你們花垣城一樣了
What's wrong with Huayuan?
和花垣城一樣 有什麼不好
Is this how you seek for help?
這就是你求人的態度
If you think women are more capable,
你不是說女人多麼厲害呢
why don't you go find help from women
為什麼不去求女人
instead of begging your husband
還不是在這裡求自己的夫君
and letting him come to me for help?
讓爍兒再來求我
I will go to women for help
我要是求女人
if you are willing to give power to women!
你也得放權給女人啊
Give power to women?
放權
Speaking of Kung Fu and art of war,
說起武藝兵法
only Pei Wujiang in your Huayuan
以前你們花垣城有個裴武姜
was quite impressive.
算一號人物
The other women on the battlefield
其他女人 上戰場
were just a joke!
那就是一個笑話
You always look down upon women,
你處處看不起女人
yet still need to send a woman out there
最終還不是要把一個女人
to solve the problem.
推出去解決問題
Who said women in Xuanhu couldn't lead the army?
誰說玄虎城沒有女人帶兵打仗
Qianqian,
芊芊
something you said was really right.
你有一句話說得很對
A woman's destiny is in her own hands.
女人的命運就該掌握在自己手裡
Women should make their own money
錢要自己賺
and lead their own army,
兵要自己帶
so that
這樣
no one will dare look down upon us again!
才不會被別人貶得一文不值
Minister Li,
李司軍
before my father passed away,
當年我父親臨終前
he gave the Xuan Token to you.
將玄符託付於您
And now I want to rejoin Xuanhu City Guards.
如今我想要回玄虎護城軍
Would you give it back to me?
你可願交還
Don't give it to her!
不能給
Give me the token.
玄符拿來
I will never forget
花老司軍的託付
what late Minister Hua told me!
屬下斷不敢忘
Minister Hua, here's the Xuan Token!
花司軍 玄符在此
The City Guards will follow your lead!
護城軍任您差遣
You!
你
Please rise!
起來吧
Finally, you are back to the army!
終於等到您重回軍營了
I can still recall your valiant
想當年 您鮮衣怒馬
and heroic presence at war!
那儀態 那氣魄
It was such a pity though that you got married too early.
就是可惜 嫁人太早了
Darling,
夫人
are you really going for the battle to Huayuan?
你真的要出征花垣城嗎
If you are,
你要是敢出兵
I... I will divorce you!
我 我就休了你
Are you kidding?
笑話
Divorce letter?
休書
I will divorce you first!
我先休了你
I've been putting up with you for a long time!
我忍你很久了
Women can't lead the army?
女人不能帶兵打仗
You may have forgotten
你大概忘了
that you once were defeated by me.
當年被我打倒
Even your horse knelt down before me!
連馬都跪下了
But don't you forget
你也不要忘了
that you are still my wife!
你還是城主夫人
I'm tired of being your wife!
城主夫人我也已經做膩了
Since it's an honor given by you,
既然是你給的榮耀
I'm okay without it.
不要也罷
From now on,
從今日起
I'll be Minister Hua;
我就是花司軍
I'm no longer the City Owner's wife!
不再是城主夫人
I have my own honor!
我有我自己的榮耀
You!
你
Rebel!
反了
Mother!
母親
They are all rebels!
全都反了
Father!
父親
Shuo!
爍兒
Even though I don't have heart disease,
為何父親沒有心疾
why my heart is so in pain?
還會心痛至此
My daughter-in-law
我這兒媳婦娶的
made my wife leave me and destroyed my family!
我妻離子散 家破人亡啊
Women in Huayuan
這花垣城的女人
are indeed evil and dangerous!
當真是紅顏禍水呀
Mother!
母親
Thank you!
謝謝你
I just made the choice I wanted.
我只是做出了我自己想要的選擇
Women should be self-reliant
女人該活出自己
and independent.
不依靠任何人
It's absolutely right!
這話沒錯
You gave me a golden token before,
當日你給了我一塊金牌
and now I'm repaying you by much more!
今日我可是百倍償還了啊
These are for your traveling expenses! Am I a good friend or not?
給你當盤纏 夠不夠義氣
How did you know that I'm going back to Huayuan?
你怎麼知道我要回花垣
All the noblewomen in the city
城主夫人出去打仗
already know that the City Owner's wife will go for a battle.
這貴婦圈裡早就傳開了
Then what about their divorce?
那 城主夫人跟城主要和離的事
That's why I think you are so amazing!
要不然說你厲害呢
You have been here just for a few days
你看 來了沒幾天
but already made your parents-in-law divorce!
就搞得公公婆婆都和離了
You know what?
我跟你說
Women in Xuanhu are all
現在玄虎城的婦人呀
trying to copy Her Majesty's way
紛紛效仿城主夫人
and make their own decisions.
都要當家做主
The City Owner got so furious after learning that!
這城主知道了 氣個半死
What happened?
怎麼了
Excuse me! Sorry!
讓一下 對不起啊
Starting today,
從即日起
women should wear long sleeves and ankle-length dress when going out.
女人上街需袖長及腕 下襬及踝
That'll be really hot in the middle of summer!
這三伏天不得熱死啊
Women are not allowed to study
女人不準進學堂
or learn how to write.
不準私自習字
Then how can we earn money?
那怎麼賺錢呀
Women are not allowed to participate in political affairs or business.
女人不得參政經商
All shops are not allowed to hire women.
商戶不得僱傭女人
That's the whole point of this notice.
原來在這兒等著呢
Every girl should begin to bind feet at age of four
四歲纏足 豆蔻束胸
and wear corset at age of 13.
無一例外
So all women will be bound,
合著都纏女人身上
and men are all free.
男人什麼都不用纏
Women are not allowed to initiate a divorce.
女人不得主動提出和離
Then we'll have no way back
那 嫁了人
after getting married!
不就等於沒有回頭路了
Abortion is forbidden!
禁止懷娠墮胎
Only this one makes sense!
就這個還靠譜
Are you kidding me?
靠譜啥 靠譜
What if the man abandons the woman?
萬一男人生米煮成熟飯不認賬
She will be screwed!
那女人多吃虧啊
Let's go!
走
What's wrong with the City Owner of Xuanhu?
這玄虎城城主怎麼回事啊
Looks like Huayuan is much better.
這 這樣看來還是花垣城好
In this case, I also want to go back to Huayuan
要不然 我也回花垣城
and live a free life like before!
過回我從前的逍遙日子
Starting today,
從即日起
men should wear long sleeves and ankle-length clothes when going out.
男人上街需袖長及腕 下襬及踝
Under this weather condition,
花垣城這天氣
they'll be muffled to death even before summer!
不到三伏天就熱死了
Tell me about it!
就是
Men are not allowed to study
男人不準進學堂
or learn how to write.
不準私自讀書習字
We can't even study in secret!
現在偷偷學也不行了
Then how can you run your school?
那您不是連私塾都辦不成了
Men are not allowed to participate in political affairs or business.
男人不準參政經商
All shops are not allowed to hire men.
商戶不得僱傭男人
Then men can only farm and get married.
那男人只能種田成親
Men are not allowed to initiate a divorce.
男人不得主動提出和離
Then we'll have no way back after getting married!
成了親就等於沒有回頭路
There are so many unfaithful women out there!
見一個愛一個的女人太多了
Women can decide for themselves
女人可以根據自己的意願
if they want to give birth.
選擇是否生下孩子
Men have no right to interfere.
男人無權干涉
Then what if the woman abandons the man?
那女人要是不認賬怎麼辦
He's not dressed properly! Arrest him!
衣衫不整 給我抓起來
Yes!
是
What's going on?
幹什麼
Move!
走
What are you doing?
你們幹什麼
Let me go!
放開我
Why are you arresting me?
你們憑什麼抓我
Did you give this order?
這是你下的命令
You said you only wanted to be the Minister of Defense
你不是隻說要當司軍
and command the army.
掌了兵權
Why did you give an unauthorized order like this?
怎麼還擅自代理政事
Are you going to take over the throne next?
下一步是不是就要繼任城主了
If I say yes,
如果我說是
what can you do?
你待如何
There's nothing I can do.
我不能如何
But Her Majesty
只是城主
has allowed men to be officials before.
之前已經准許男人做官
People in Huayuan have become more open-minded.
花垣城民風已經開化
How could you disobey her decree?
你怎麼能違揹她的政令
Was that my mother's decree
這到底是母親的政令
or Chen Qianqian's?
還是陳芊芊的政令
That was only a rule that Chen Qianqian made
這不過是母親生病時
when mother was ill.
陳芊芊代理政務所制定的規矩
It was completely wrong!
這都是錯的
I'll let Huayuan
我要讓花垣城
get back to the way it was!
恢復到以前的樣子
As a filler-in,
你如今代理政事
you don't care about right or wrong,
不管對錯
but only go against Qianqian!
只管與芊芊對著幹
Go take a look for yourself!
你去街上看一看
Not only men,
不光是男人
but women are also unhappy about this!
女人對此也十分不滿
What you are doing is totally
你這是倒行逆施啊
against people's will!
違背民意
I'm fully in control
現在花垣城的權力
My will is people's will!
我的意願 才是民意
Chuchu,
楚楚
this is not how I taught you
我之前任司學時
when I was the Minister of Education!
可不是這般教導你的
But you are not on that position anymore.
可你現在已經不是司學了
And I'm no longer the previous Second Princess.
我也不是以前的二郡主了
I will listen to no one!
我再也不會受任何人擺佈
Time will tell
事實會證明
that Qianqian was right!
芊芊才是對的
Don't you dare mention Chen Qianqian in front of me!
不許在我面前提陳芊芊
Chen Qianqian,
陳芊芊
why can't you just leave me alone?!
你怎麼總是陰魂不散
Su, will you eat something?
蘇兄 你還是吃一些吧
You've been losing weight.
近幾日你都消瘦了
Master!
大當家的
I know you just pretended to be nice!
之前裝這麼好心
Now, you'll finally kill me.
現在終於忍不住要殺我了
Turn around.
轉過去
You are free.
走吧
You'll set me free?
你要放我走
All you want in your life
你的一生追求
is to put your ambition to good use.
不過就是為了施展你的抱負
Since Huayuan is no longer home to you,
如今花垣城容不下你了
why don't you stay in Xuanhu?
不如你就待在玄虎城
You may have an opportunity to display your talents here.
也許還有你的一番用武之地
Su, you should thank Master.
蘇兄 快謝謝大當家的
Why are you doing this?
為什麼
Will you stop asking "why"?
你一天哪兒有那麼多為什麼
I will go back to Huayuan for a battle.
我要回花垣打仗去了
I can't bring a burden like you with me.
不可能帶著你這個拖油瓶吧
Don't tell me that you also want to go back to Huayuan,
你可別告訴我說你要回花垣城
where's no room for men now.
現在花垣可容不下男人
What do you mean?
為何這樣說
What happened in Huayuan?
花垣怎麼了
Anything happened to the Second Princess?
二郡主發生了什麼事
Men are not allowed to study
男人不準進學堂
or learn how to write.
不準私自讀書習字
Men are not allowed to participate in political affairs or business.
男人不準參政經商
All shops are not allowed to hire men.
不準僱傭男人
Men are not allowed to initiate a divorce.
男人不準主動提出和離
This is not the Second Princess' idea!
這不是二郡主的主意
Believe whatever you want.
信不信由你吧
Are men also not allowed to lead the army?
是不是也不準男人領兵
This is something only you would order!
這都是你才能幹出來的事
How come
如今
the Second Princess has become like this?
二郡主怎麼會變成這樣
I would order?
我
Why do you always blame me
你怎麼喜歡什麼事
for everything?
都往我身上推呀
I was once
當年
dressed as a woman to join the election of lieutenant.
我男扮女裝考副將
You took me out from the crowds and beat me up. I almost died!
你將我揪出來毒打 險些廢掉
So
如今
don't bother acting like a good person now.
你充什麼好人
Why don't you just kill me?
你為何不直接殺了我
So it was
所以是
Chen Chuchu who saved you from Chen Qianqian.
陳楚楚把你從陳芊芊手上救走
No wonder you hate me this much.
怪不得你一直針對我
Alright, now things are clear!
行吧 破案了
Actually it's not that hard to untie your mind knot.
其實想解你的心結也不難
How about this? You can go back to Huayuan with me.
這樣 你同我一起回花垣
I'll let you see yourself
在路上
how I treat Zi Rui and Meng Guo on the way.
你看看我是怎麼對梓銳跟孟過的
Then you'll know
便知道
the current me is not anymore the previous me.
現在的我還是不是當初的我
Everybody was once ignorant.
人都有年少無知的時候嘛
Please forgive me for my ignorance
你就當我當初不懂事
and for hurting you.
傷害了你
I'll make it up to you
以前欠你的
for what I owe you.
現在還
What took you so long to untie it?
你怎麼解這麼久還解不開
Where's the maid who served me before?
以前一直給我更衣的侍女呢
Your Majesty, please don't be angry!
城主息怒
Your Majesty,
稟告城主
the maid who served you before was a dowry of your wife.
那是城主夫人的陪嫁
She has moved to the Minister's Mansion
已經跟隨城主夫人
with Her Majesty.
一起回司軍府了
Alright, I'll untie it myself.
行了 我自己來
Go get me a basin of warm water. I'll wash my feet.
你去幫我端盆熱水 我要洗腳
Wash your feet?
洗腳
Her Majesty said
城主夫人說
she bought the basin with her dowry,
洗腳盆也是用她的嫁妝買的
so she took it away.
她拿回去了
What?
什麼
She didn't even leave me a basin!
連個洗腳盆都不給我留下
Then why can't you get me a new one?
那你不能拿個新的來嗎
Her Majesty
從前採買物件
was in charge of purchasing.
都是城主夫人安排的
But she's left,
現在城主夫人走了
and nobody has been assigned to do it!
誰也接不了手啊
Useless!
一群廢物
Pass my order. Let Young Master come to see me.
傳令 讓少君來見我
You can at least do this, can't you?
這點事你總能幹了吧
Yes! Yes!
是 是
Look, what a mess Chen Qianqian has made!
你看那個陳芊芊惹出多大的禍
Can't believe she convinced your mother to do such a ridiculous thing!
竟讓你母親做出這種荒唐的事
All women of entire Xuanhu City
現在全玄虎城的女人
are copying her behaviors now!
都跟著反了
Now I understand
我現在終於知道
why Chen Qianqian is the Third Princess.
陳芊芊為什麼是三公主了
The First Princess is worshiped by the city, and the Second is worshiped by the country,
郡主傾城 公主傾國
yet the ego of the Third is bigger than both the city and the country.
兩座城都裝不下她
It was mother's decision
母親重任司軍
to be the Minister of Defense again.
是她自己的決定
But all women wanted to divorce their husbands
而全城婦人紛紛和丈夫和離
because
是因為
you issued an unfair decree.
您頒佈了不公的規定
It wasn't Qianqian's fault.
這怎麼能怪芊芊
But nothing happened until Chen Qianqian
這些事都是那個陳芊芊來了以後
showed up!
才發生的
It only shows that the problems were already there.
那這隻能說明這些矛盾已經存在
And Qianqian just made
而芊芊只是讓這些矛盾
them emerge.
浮出水面而已
I don't think there used to be problems.
哪裡有什麼矛盾哪
Your mother and I loved each other very much.
我跟你母親感情多好啊
Why did you marry my mother?
您當年為什麼要娶我母親
Why do you ask?
你問這個幹嗎
Have you forgotten?
您不會已經忘記了吧
Of course not!
當然沒有
I met your mother in the military camp.
當年 我跟你母親在軍營相識
During a martial arts training,
我們切磋武藝
she pinned me on the ground and beat me up!
她把我按在地上打
I couldn't get it over with,
那時候 我心裡記恨
thinking after I got back to Xuanhu,
想到回到玄虎城
I'd win the next round.
我一定要扳回一城
But after I returned to Xuanhu,
誰知道我回到玄虎城之後
I found that she was actually a woman!
竟發現她是女兒身
She was not only beautiful and skillful in Kung Fu,
不僅人漂亮 武藝高
but also good at playing polo!
還會打馬球
When she was on the field,
你母親在球場上
she was swift as the wind and quick as the lightning.
馳驟擊拂 風驅電逝
I'd never seen such a woman.
我從未見過如此女子
So charming!
俊啊
So, Xiaoqian is pretty much just like her!
那 和小千倒是頗為相似啊
How can your Xiaoqian compare to your mother?
你的小芊可比不上
Back then, your mother's eyes were like stars,
當年 你母親眼睛裡是有星星的
shining and shining!
一閃一閃的
Then Xiaoqian's eyes are just like that!
那這跟小千真是一模一樣啊
However, it's a pity
只可惜呀
that you mother was not
你母親婚後
as alive as before after we got married.
不像以前那麼鮮活了
I heard
我聽傳言說
that after you married my mother,
自從您娶了母親之後
in order to make her happy,
為了討她歡心
you planted these magnolias in the yard.
便在園中種下了這些木蘭花
But I don't understand
可是我不明白
why you didn't
為什麼從不將木蘭花
keep them inside?
養在室內啊
Magnolia has a unique elegant and refined quality,
木蘭清麗脫俗
only the infinite open environment can match it.
唯有這廣闊天地才能配得上它
If you keep it inside, it'll suppress its charm.
養在室內 豈不是俗氣了
Since you fell in love with a woman
您既然傾心的是那個騎著戰馬
who was so attractive and brave on the horseback,
不可一世的女人
then why would you require her
那為什麼要求她在家相夫教子
to be a stereotypical housewife
賢良淑德
and become someone you don't like?
變成您不喜歡的人呢
My mother
母親是為了您
lost her charm for you.
所以才失去了往日的光芒
But
而您呢
what have you done for her?
您為她做了什麼
Do you know what she really wants
您知道她真正想要什麼
and what she really wants to become?
想成為什麼樣子嗎
Before, for the sake of my heart disease,
先前為了醫治韓某心疾
our troops had to hide the real power and endure the humiliation.
眾將士只得隱藏實力 飽受屈辱
And now,
如今
Chen Chuchu, the Second Princess of Huayuan, breaks her promise
花垣城二郡主陳楚楚背信棄義
and seizes the black stone minerals she agreed to sell to us.
扣押原本要賣給我們的烏石礦
Our men in Xuanhu cannot be bullied like this!
我玄虎男兒 豈能任人欺耍
Let's go to Huayuan City and fight for justice!
我們一起去花垣城 討個公道
Fight for justice!
討個公道
I promise you
我保證
that I will bring all of you back alive
將你們一個不落的帶回來
to reunite with your family!
和你們的夫人 孩子團聚
Thank you, Young Master!
謝少君
I heard that the women all wanted a divorce.
不是說婦人們紛紛要和離嗎
It doesn't sound like it was true.
怎麼看起來一點也不像啊
Your Majesty, these men will be in for a tough battle
城主 這畢竟是去花垣城奪礦
to fight for the mine in Huayuan.
硬碰硬的那種
It could be a one-way trip.
說不好 就是生死訣別
No matter how much they fight,
平日鬧得再厲害
when something important happens, the husband and wife are still united.
大事當前 還是能夫妻一心
You are also here to see off Her Majesty, aren't you?
您 不是也來送城主夫人的嗎
Shut up!
你給我閉嘴
Greetings to you, Minister Hua!
見過花司軍
Mother, this is Su Ziying,
母親 這是蘇子嬰
the lieutenant I selected for you.
是我給你選的副將
But you need to be careful when you use him.
就是用的時候你得小心點
Please rise!
起來吧
This is ridiculous!
豈有此理
Your Majesty, calm down!
城主切勿動怒
A country
一個城邦
can run as normal
沒有城主夫人不是什麼大事
without a queen,
離開她照樣轉
but it can't without a king.
但不能沒有城主
You are the City Owner.
您才是一城之主
You need to take good care of yourself!
可千萬要保重身體啊
Stop talking!
你給我閉嘴
Pack my stuff, I'll go with them.
收拾行囊 我要隨行
Yes!
是
Your Highness, our spy sent a message
二郡主 探子傳來消息
that Xuanhu army has stationed in the suburb
說玄虎一行人駐紮郊外
and will arrive here in a couple of days.
兩三日便可到達
I asked Xuanhu to hand over Chen Qianqian,
我讓玄虎城交出陳芊芊
yet they send out army to fight me!
他們反倒派人來與我作對
What's good about Chen Qianqian?
陳芊芊究竟哪裡好
Even people in Xuanhu are bewitched by her!
竟然連玄虎城的人都被她迷惑
Report, Minster Pei!
啟稟裴司軍
The Princess Royal disappeared!
大郡主不知去向
She's probably gone to find the Third Princess!
很可能是投奔三公主去了
Son of a bitch!
混賬
There's no Third Princess in Huayuan!
花垣城早就沒有三公主了
Yes! I'll remember!
是 屬下謹記
Yuanyuan!
長姐
Yuanyuan, are you okay?
長姐 你沒事吧
Did Chuchu give you a hard time?
楚楚有沒有為難你啊
Qianqian, don't worry!
芊芊 你放心
We got out from a secret passageway
她還沒來得及對我怎麼樣
in my mansion before she got a chance
我們三人就從我府上的密道
to do anything to me.
逃了出來
Secret passageway?
密道
I have a secret passageway that directly leads to outside of the city.
我府上有一密道 可直通城外
It was built for emergency just like this.
就是為了防止今日的情形
If Her Highness looks out for herself
我們少城主要像大郡主一樣
like the Princess Royal does, then...
愛惜生命 那這
Why didn't you bring mother along?
那為何不帶母親一起出來
After Chuchu learned that she's not Her Majesty's real daughter,
這楚楚得知自己並非城主親生
nothing could hold her back anymore.
便徹底沒了顧忌
She took over the City Guards,
直接下手奪了護城軍
claimed that Her Majesty was ill,
替城主稱病
seized the black stone mine,
還切斷了礦脈
and put all the black stones in her mansion.
將礦石全部運往府中
Then what about Pei Heng?
那裴恆呢
Mr. Pei has been detained.
裴公子 他也被囚禁了
Chuchu keeps making mistakes!
楚楚真是一步錯步步錯
Yuanyuan, don't worry!
長姐 你放心
I borrowed some troops
這次我從玄虎城
from Xuanhu this time.
借了一些人馬回來
I'm sure I can save mother and Pei Heng.
一定能夠救出母親跟裴恆的
But, you only brought a few people here...
可是 你就帶了這麼些人過來
We already did you a big favor by lending you the troops.
我們玄虎能出人出力就不錯了
As a girl, you should feel grateful
一個小丫頭 還挑三揀四的
instead of putting ourselves down!
長他人志氣 滅自己威風
Father.
父親
You are here, too.
你也來了
Step aside.
退下
You misunderstood me.
您誤會了
I just don't wanna see Qianqian and Chuchu fight each other.
我是怕芊芊和楚楚她們硬碰硬
In my opinion, we should conquer the city.
依我看 還是攻城為上
Xuanhu is known as its smelting and gunpowder production.
玄虎城以冶煉和火藥營生
We have very powerful and competitive force.
戰力非凡 能夠以一敵十
When we enter the city, we can split into two troops,
進城後 咱們兵分兩路
one to save your mother and Pei Heng,
一路去救你母親 和裴恆
the other
還有一路
to find out where the black stones are.
打探礦石消息
But I don't want
可花垣百姓
to hurt innocent citizens in Huayuan City.
我不想傷及無辜
I have an idea that can make us win without a battle.
嬰嬰有一計 可以兵不血刃
Your Highness, you can pretend to be my hostage.
三公主 你可假裝被我拿下
I'll take you into the city,
由我帶你進入城中
and then we'll find a chance to capture the Second Princess.
我們再找機會反拿二郡主
That way, with the commander being caught,
如此 擒賊先擒王
none of the citizens will get hurt.
城中百姓必無傷亡
Double Agent Strategy!
反間計
It will be the most efficient method,
確實是最見效的一種辦法
but also one that may make me die the quickest.
也是我死得最快的一種
You've tried to kill Xiaoqian several times.
之前你多次設計陷害小千性命
How am I supposed to trust you this time?
這次要我如何信你
Trust me or not, it's up to the Third Princess.
信不信 皆由三公主定奪
I'll go with you.
我陪你去
Young Master is a martial arts expert.
少君武藝高強
If I pretended that I defeated both of you,
我若佯裝將你和三公主一起制服
it wouldn't be convincing.
可信度太低了
Alright,
好
I'll go with you alone.
我一個人跟你去
After all, we can't attack the city,
畢竟 不能火藥強攻
or the citizens of Huayuan
否則 花垣城的百姓
will suffer a lot.
必定遭受牽連
You are really willing to risk your own life
你當真願意為了花垣城的百姓
for Huayuan's citizens?
賭上自己的性命
I'm not.
不願意
But I have no other choices.
可我沒有辦法
Your Highness,
三公主
I will serve you and be loyal to you for my whole life!
小人此生 必死生追隨
Rise, please!
起來吧
Every time you knelt to me, something bad would happen.
你每次拜我 我都沒什麼好事
Your Highness, don't worry!
少城主放心
I'll bring some people to help you make the plan work.
我會帶人裡應外合 配合你們
My husband and I will go save your mother.
我們夫妻二人去救你母親
Be safe!
一路平安
Open the gate! Open the gate, now!
開城門 快開城門
(Huayuan City) Stop! Stop!
站住 站住
Who are you?
你是誰
I'm Su Ziying!
在下蘇子嬰
The Second Princess ordered me to catch Chen Qianqian.
奉二郡主之命捉拿陳芊芊
Let me through!
還不放行
Su Ziying, let Qianqian go!
蘇子嬰 放下芊芊
Come on!
走
Young Master, let's go.
少君 我們先走吧
The Princess Royal's secret passageway is so well-concealed.
大郡主這密道真隱蔽呀
Young Master, the inner city is heavily guarded.
少君 城內重兵把守
If anything goes wrong,
如若出現差池
how can we get out of here?
我們怎麼脫身啊
No worry. Xiaoqian will figure out a way.
放心 小千肯定有辦法
She's the screenwriter.
她是編劇
What's screenwriter?
編劇是什麼意思
Someone who makes up stories.
就是 編瞎話的
Who is it?
什麼人
Let's split.
分頭行動
Okay!
好
Let's go.
走
Honey,
夫人
Shuo said I've ignored you for too long.
爍兒說我忽略你太久了
Will you keep ignoring me? Starting right now!
你能不能繼續忽略我 就現在
Report! Your Highness, they are here!
啟稟二郡主 人已帶到
Bring them in.
帶進來吧
Yes!
是
Your Highness.
二郡主
Though I was caught by Chen Qianqian,
小人先前雖被陳芊芊擒拿
I never forgot the mission you assigned to me.
但始終不忘二郡主的使命
I pretended to surrender and spied on her,
臥薪嚐膽 假意投靠
finally got a chance to capture her.
趁機將她擒來
Please punish her as you will!
但憑您處置
Good!
很好
Lock her up first!
都先關起來
Who is it?
誰
Don't move!
別動
You are such a good-for-nothing!
成事不足 敗事有餘的廢物
How dare you betray me?
好一個恩將仇報
Don't you remember how I saved you before?
你忘了當年我是怎麼救的你
I will never forget
二郡主的恩情
that you saved my life!
小人沒齒難忘
I once thought
小人也曾以為
that you were kind and thoughtful,
二郡主您善解人意
yet the Third Princess was evil and wicked.
三公主惡貫滿盈
But now, I changed my mind.
可如今 小人不是這樣想的
For all this time,
這一路走來
everything you did
您的所作所為
reminded me of the old Chen Qianqian.
讓我想起了當日的陳芊芊
Will you stop criticizing me?
你打歸打 你別罵人行不行
Chen Chuchu,
陳楚楚
it's not too late
回頭是岸
to make things right.
現在還來得及
Your life is still in danger,
你現在自身難保
yet you are trying to persuade me?
還有工夫來勸我
So funny!
可笑
You think I'd sit here waiting for death?
你們以為我會坐以待斃嗎
Mr. Pei! Mr. Pei!
公子 公子
Something happened in the city.
城中出事了
Whatever Chuchu wants to do,
楚楚要做什麼
just let her.
就隨她去吧
I don't care anymore.
我也不想再管了
Not the Second Princess, but the Third!
不是二郡主 是三公主
What?
什麼
The Third Princess led a small troop
三公主帶著一小撮人馬
and came back from Xuanhu
從玄虎城回來
to ambush the Second Princess.
詐降二郡主
But instead, she was surrounded by the Second Princess,
沒想到被二郡主甕中捉鱉
and her life is in danger right now!
性命堪憂
Where are the City Guards?
護城軍呢
Some headed to the inner city
朝城中去了
and some are on their way here.
還有一夥 朝咱們來了
We were here to find
咱們不就是來找
the City Owner of Huayuan.
花垣城主的下落嗎
We didn't find her!
這是找到了嗎
We are locked up with her!
這是被關在一起
I'm the City Owner of Xuanhu.
在下玄虎城主
This is my wife,
這位是我的夫人
the Minister of Defense of Xuanhu.
玄虎城司軍
You must be the City Owner of Huayuan.
您應該就是花垣城主吧
And this one must be your husband.
這位 想必就是您的夫君吧
I'm Her Majesty's servant.
小人是城主的侍從
I'm sorry!
多有得罪
I see that you two are pretty close,
我見二人舉止親密
so I thought...
還以為
I thought Xuanhu city attached more importance to men
你們玄虎城不是以男子為尊
and didn't allow women to be officials.
女人不能當官嗎
How come your wife is the Minister of Defense?
為什麼你的夫人是司軍啊
It was an emergency.
事發突然
I took the job at the last minute.
我也是臨危受命
I see that you are such a brave woman,
我見夫人英姿颯爽
and you act like the head of household.
做事頗有一家之主風範
I think you are the one calls the shots in your family, right?
想必平日也是你當家吧
How are your children?
家裡的孩子都還好吧
Are they filial and capable?
都還 孝順能幹吧
They are indeed capable.
的確能幹
See, one of them even invited you two here.
這不 把二位也請過來了嗎
And they are
孝順嘛
also filial.
倒也孝順
In case I'm too old to take care of myself,
怕我年紀大了出意外
one of them sent lots of guards to watch me.
這不 還派了重兵把守
Are you stupid?
你是不是虎
Your Majesties,
二位城主
why don't you talk about your children's marriage?
還是聊聊兩位少城主的婚事吧
We can talk about that!
這個可以聊
After I finish the business here,
等這次忙完了
I'll bring Qianqian back to Xuanhu
芊芊跟我們回玄虎
and hold another wedding for her and Shuo.
再給他們辦次婚禮
I've even picked a new mansion for them.
新的府邸 我都想好在哪兒了
Wait!
不對
Han Shuo has married into my family.
韓爍已經入贅我們花垣
He should stay in Huayuan with us in the future.
那將來得住在我們花垣城
How did he marry into your family?
怎麼能是入贅呢
We've made a deal.
之前已經說好了
Han Shuo married into my family
韓爍入贅我們花垣
to get the black stone mining right in return
以換取烏石礦的開採權
and make the two cities become friends.
以修兩城之好
But we didn't get the black stone minerals,
後來也沒有給我們礦啊
so he can't marry into your family.
自然不能算是入贅
When they have a baby, who should also be surnamed Han.
以後生了孩子 也要姓韓
No! It should be Chen!
不行 還是姓陳
No!
不行
Our family has a City Owner position to pass down.
我們家可是有城主之位要繼承的
What a coincidence! So does mine!
巧了 我家也有
How about this then?
那這樣
If it's a boy, he'll be surnamed Han. If it's a girl, she'll be surnamed Chen.
男孩姓韓 女孩姓陳
Your Majesty, this is a good idea!
城主 這倒是個好辦法
Then you have to promise
那你們得承諾
that you'll love your granddaughter as you do to your grandson.
疼愛孫女要像疼愛孫子一樣
As long as you can love your grandson
只要你能像疼愛孫女一樣
as you do to your granddaughter!
疼愛我孫子
That's easy.
這好辦
If they are all surnamed Chen, I'll love them equally!
都姓陳 我一樣疼愛
Are you kidding?
這話說的
If they are all surnamed Han, I'll also love them equally!
都隨我姓 我也都疼
We are all family here! Stop fighting!
都是一家人就別吵了
Let's toss the dice to decide what to do?
咱們扔色子決定吧
What are you waiting for?
都愣著幹什麼
Arrest Chen Qianqian, now!
還不拿下陳芊芊
The Third Princess is Her Majesty's real daughter!
三公主才是城主的親生女兒
Though we take orders from you,
我們雖然聽命於裴司軍
we can't hurt the Third Princess!
但也不能對三公主動手啊
Your Third Princess
你們的三公主
used to be arrogant, bossy and cruel.
往日可是囂張跋扈 荒唐無度
She's a shame of Huayuan!
是花垣之恥
That was in the past.
這都是陳年舊賬了
But I admit that I used to be that way.
不過我認
Chen Chuchu,
陳楚楚
you disobeyed mother and persecuted your sisters.
你忤逆母親 殘害姐妹
You don't deserve to be a princess of Huayuan!
不配為花垣郡主
How about you then?
那你呢
You even brought Xuanhu's army in here!
你還帶著玄虎城的人攻了回來
But I didn't hurt
可我沒有殺害花垣城
any citizen of our city!
任何一個百姓
When you were in charge of the city affairs,
你在代理政務期間
you put Huayuan in such a chaos!
卻把花垣城搞得雞犬不寧
That was your excuse!
強詞奪理
What are you afraid of?
心虛什麼
City Guards, take my order!
護城軍聽令
Kill Chen Qianqian!
殺了陳芊芊
Well...
這
I think the Third Princess' words make sense.
我覺得 三公主說得有點道理
That's right. People all support the Third Princess.
就是 三公主深得民心
But the Second Princess always rakes up the past.
二郡主卻只是翻陳年舊曆
Have you read
那本傳聞中的三公主
"The Rumored Third Princess"?
你看了沒有
I think the Third Princess also
我覺得三公主也挺不容易的
had her own struggle.
她有她的苦衷
This is a military order!
這是軍令
What if we don't acknowledge your commandership?
如果我們不認你當司軍
So we don't have to listen to you anymore, do we?
是不是就不用聽命於你的軍令了
Have you lost your mind?
你們瘋了
I'm a descendant of the Pei family!
我是裴家後嗣
My last name is Pei!
我姓裴
But what you are doing
可你今日的所作所為
is against Her Majesty's decree
違反了城主的命令
and disturbing the livelihood of our people,
擾亂花垣城民的生計
as well as in defiance of late Minister Pei's will!
罔顧已故裴司軍的遺志